Nil Garcés de Marcilla Escubedo

Address: Av. Riera de Cassoles 30, 08012 (Bcn)

Mobile: (+34) 649 37 26 89 Email: xetaxe@gmail.com

Personal website: www.nilgarces.dev LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/nilgarces

Full stack developer well versed in TypeScript, React, Next.js, Node.js and both SQL and no-SQL paradigms. Also interested in Golang.

Proven experience in consulting and project planning/management.

Persistent problem-solver and fast learner with a solid mathematical and analytical background.

ACADEMIC TRAINING

2019 - 2020 M.Sc. "Math. et applications"

THESIS AREA: TOPOLOGICAL DATA
ANALYSIS (CLUSTER. METHODS)
Université de Nantes (France)

2018 - 2019 M.Sc. in Secondary Teaching
SPECIALIZATION: MATHEMATICS
Common UB-UAB-UPC-UPF-UOC

2014 - 2018 B.Sc. in Mathematics
MENTION: MATHEMATICS (G: 8.3)
University of Barcelona

LANGUAGES

CATALAN Native (Certificat C2)

Spanish Native

ENGLISH Excellent (CAE: Grade A, C2)

FRENCH Very good

GERMAN Intermediate (learning)

COMPUTER SKILLS

Personal website: www.nilgarces.dev

Github: github.com/xetaxe

- Essentials: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Git+GitHub

- Frontend: React, React Query, Zustand, Next.js, Tailwind, Sass, Figma
- Backend: Node.js, Express, Golang
- DB: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Prisma, MongoDB
- Testing: Jest, React Testing Library
- Build/Deploy: Vite, Docker, Github Actions
- Other lang: Python, C

EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2021 – CURRENTLY SDP Spain, Valldoreix (Barcelona)

Software consultant

- Software consultant implementing and developing ERA, our own customisable software tool that helps companies manage their Time & Attendance efficiently.
- I launched several implementations with international clients and aided in existing projects, always providing feedback for product iteration.

JANUARY 2021 – JUNE 2021 SDG Group, Barcelona

Data analyst

- Co-responsible of a big data ETL project (with Qlik/SQL) where weekly data reports and forecasts were generated based on previous sales data.
- Participant in a data analysis and visualization project where PowerBI was used to track product performance.

MARCH 2020 – JULY 2020 Université de Nantes, Nantes

Math internship

- I studied the theoretical foundations of Topological Data Analysis (TDA).
- I got familiarized with the most important DS/ML concepts and Python libraries (Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, NumPy & SciPy, Pandas).
- I collaborated and documented the implementation of a new clustering algorithm (ToMATo algorithm) in the GUDHI library.

JULY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018 VGG Aplicaciones, Barcelona

Software engineer

- Researcher and programmer in a (fixed-term) project where we studied the viability of using drones in warehouses to do various tasks autonomously. It involved experimenting with various drone SDKs in Java (Android Studio).

OTHER ACTIVITIES

- Three-times participant in HackUPC: finalist x2 and one winner prize: (Devpost: xetaxe)
- UB representative at the International Math Competition (IMC, Bulgaria) in 2016 & 2017.
- Since 2016, I work on my own musical solo project, in which I compose, play and record pieces for classical guitar (Spotify: Nil Garcés)